Guide to the Arthur Willert Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arthur Willert papers
1907-1973
MS 720
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11
(30 boxes, 1 folio)
Correspondence, writings, notes, memoranda, and printed matter of Arthur Willert, British journalist and diplomat. His correspondence is largely political, particularly during his tenure as chief correspondent of the London Times in the United States (1910-1920) and as representative of the Ministry of Information (1917-1918). As a member of United Kingdom delegations to various international conferences (1921-1934) his memoranda and other writings offer a view of European political affairs. From 1939-1945 he was Head of the Ministry of Information Office for the Southern Region. In addition to his newspaper articles, he wrote for magazines, lectured in the United States (1936-1939) and wrote four books on international politics. In the papers are printed copies and drafts of articles, drafts of two books and a draft for an unidentified book. The correspondence of Florence S. Willert, his wife, includes forty-five letters from Eleanor Roosevelt. His correspondents include D. D. Braham, Herbert Croly, Geoffrey Dawson, Lord Northcliffe, H. W. Steed, Sir Campbell Stuart, Robert Wilberforce, Evelyn Wrench.
Willert, Arthur, Sir, 1882-1973
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the estate of Arthur Willert, 1974.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Personal and Memorabilia.
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Personal and Memorabilia.
I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1910-1957
II. WRITINGS, (1907-1920) - (1935-1939) - 1964
III. PERSONAL AND MEMORABILIA, 1909-1973
FOLIO
Scope and Contents
The Arthur Willert Papers are an important source for documenting the history of Anglo-American relations during the two decades immediately prior to and following World War I. Willert's dispatches to the editors of the London Times and letters to friends provide an informed assessment of a variety of subjects and personalities relating to Anglo-American relations and America's entry into World War I. The papers merit attention not only for the insight they provide for a vital period in Anglo-American relations, but also because Willert himself emerges as a figure of interest whose activities as a reporter and propagandist played a part in determining the course of Anglo-American relations.
The papers are arranged in three series: I. Correspondence; II. Writings; III. Personal and Memorabilia.
CORRESPONDENCE is divided into three sections: General Correspondence, Mrs. Arthur Willert's Correspondence, and Northcliffe Mission Correspondence. General Correspondence contains the major portion of Willert's correspondence. Correspondents of note in General Correspondence include: D.D. Brahm, Times Foreign Editor, 1912-1914 (23 to AW/ 29 from); Geoffrey Dawson, Times Editor, 1911-1919 (121 to AW/ 158 from); Cecil A. Spring-Rice, British Ambassador to the U.S., 1912-1918 (10 to AW); Wickham Steed, Times Foreign Editor, 1914-1919 (28 to AW/ 42 from); William Wiseman, British Foreign Office Chief Intelligence Officer in U.S., 1917 (7 to AW/ 12 from).
The matters discussed in Willert's correspondence with the London Times staff (Brahm, Dawson, Steed) related primarily to Anglo-American relations and U.S. domestic politics. Subjects include: President Wilson's personality and political ability; U.S. policy towards Mexico; U.S. intervention in World War I; the Northcliffe Mission; U.S. labor, coal, and transport problems; the Balfour Mission; German propaganda in the U.S.; the Lusitania's sinking; German war intrigues; and British propaganda.
Subjects discussed in Willert's correspondence with Spring-Rice and Wiseman include: Wilson's Mexico policy; Willert's role as a propagandist; Anglo-American relations; the London Naval Conference. An interesting letter from Willert to Lady Astor (1914) discusses President Wilson's physical condition.
Mrs. Arthur Willert's Correspondence contains letters which are primarily social in nature. These include forty-five letters from Eleanor Roosevelt (1932-1955) and sixty letters from Arthur Willert (1918-1950).
The Northcliffe Mission (British war mission to the U.S., 1917) Correspondence consists of approximately seventy dispatches sent between the Mission and the British Foreign Office between July and December, 1917. The subjects of the dispatches relate primarily to the acquisition of war material and Anglo-American relations. Appendix I is a detailed list of the correspondents and people mentioned in the Northcliffe Mission Correspondence.
Series II, WRITINGS, includes clippings of articles Willert wrote while serving as Washington correspondent of the London Times (1910-1920); reprints of his magazine articles, book reviews, and lectures; notebooks and appointment books. The most interesting materials in this series are his memoranda and notes written in his capacity as a Times correspondent and Foreign Office press officer. Important subjects include: British propaganda in the U.S., 1914; an account of a conversation between Spring-Rice and Robert Lansing on Anglo-American relations, 1915; President Wilson, 1917; the Democratic Convention, 1920; the Washington Conference, 1921; the Lausanne Conference, 1932; the Geneva Disarmament Conference, 1932; and conversations with Franklin Roosevelt, 1936, 1939.
Series III, PERSONAL AND MEMORABILIA, consists primarily of souvenir materials: credentials, menus, invitations, and a set of The Intimate Papers of Colonel House with notes in Willert's handwriting.
The Arthur Willert Papers were received by Yale University in 1974, the result of a bequest by Sir Arthur Willert.
Biographical / Historical
Sir Arthur Willert was born on May 19, 1882 in Oxford, England. He received his education at Eton and Balliol College, Oxford, and in 1906 began a career in journalism as a member of the London Times staff. After brief periods in Paris, Berlin, Washington, and London Willert was appointed chief correspondent of the London Times in the United States, a position he held from 1910 to 1920. His work for the Times was interrupted during 1917-1918 when he served as Secretary of the British War Mission in Washington and representative of the Ministry of Information.
While in the United States Willert's amiable personality and talent as a journalist won him a large number of contacts in influential government and private circles. Among those with whom he established friendships were: William Howard Taft, Elihu Root, Edward M. House, Robert Lansing, Frank Polk, and the young Franklin Roosevelt. During World War I Willert's contacts, combined with his firsthand knowledge of American public opinion, enabled him to supply the British government with valuable information on American politics, foreign policy, and public opinion. Of equal importance to Britain was Willert's skill in acting as an unofficial interpreter of the British view-point to American officials.
In 1921 Willert left the Times to become Head of the News Department and Press Officer of the British Foreign Office. As part of his duties Willert was a member of the United Kingdom's delegation to the Washington Naval Conference (1921-1922), the London Economic Conference (1924), the London Naval Conference (1930), the Geneva Disarmament Conference (1932-1934), and to meetings of the League of Nations between 1929 and 1934.
Resigning from the Foreign Office in 1935 Willert devoted his time to writing and lecturing on British foreign policy and the need for collective security in the face of the increasing militarization of Germany. At the outbreak of World War II he became Head of the Ministry of Information office for the Southern Region, a post he held until 1945.
Sir Arthur died on March 11, 1973.
His published works include: Aspects of British Foreign Policy (1928), The Frontiers of England (1935), The Empire in the World (joint, 1937), The Road to Safety (1952), Washington and other Memoirs (1972).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
APPENDIX: NORTHCLIFFE MISSION CORRESPONDENCE IN THE ARTHUR WILLERT PAPERS
Balfour, A.J. --- Asquith, Captain
Buchan, John --- Baillie, ____
Churchill, Winston --- Barclay, Colville
Cook, Kemball --- Black, Sir Frederick
Hall, Henry Noble --- Brand, Robert
Hudson, Sir Robert --- Brooks, Sidney
Lausanne, --- Caird, Andrew
Lever, Sir Hardman --- Dawson, Geoffrey
Lloyd George, David --- Garrod, Heathcote
Long, Walter --- Gordon, Sir Charles
Northcliffe, Lady --- Harmsworth, Cecil
Phillips, C.J. --- House, Edward M.
Reading, Earl of --- Japp, Henry
Smuts, General Jan --- Kent, Sir Stephenson
Stone, Melville --- Law, Bonar
Wiseman, Sir William --- McAdoo, William
--- McCormick, Medill
--- MacLachlan, Brigadier General James
--- Royden, Sir Thomas
--- Spring Rice, Sir Cecil
--- Stettinius, Edward R.
--- Stone, Melville
--- Tardieu, André
--- Willert, Sir Arthur
Times (London, England); World War, 1914-1918; Europe; Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- United States; United States -- Foreign relations -- Great Britain; Diplomats; Journalists; Balfour, Arthur James, 1848-1930; Braham, Dudley Disraeli, 1875-1951; Bucham, John, 1875-1940; Churchill, Winston, 1874-1965; Cook, Kemball; Corbett, Howard; Croly, Herbert David, 1869-1930; Dawson, Geoffrey, 1874-1944; Murray, Arthur C. (Arthur Cecil), 1879-1962; Grigg, John, 1924-2001; Hall, Henry Noble, 1872-1949; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938; Hudson, Robert Arundell, 1864-1927; Lever, Samuel Hardman, 1869-1947; Lloyd George, David, 1863-1945; Long, Walter Hume Long, Viscount, 1854-1924; Northcliffe, Alfred Harmsworth, Viscount, 1865-1922; Percy of Newcastle, Eustace Percy, Baron, 1887-1958; Phillips, C. J.; Reading, Gerald Rufus Isaacs, Marquess of, 1889-1960; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Smuts, Jan Christiaan, 1870-1950; Spring Rice, Cecil, Sir, 1859-1918; Steed, Henry Wickham, 1871-1956; Stone, Melville Elijah, 1848-1929; Stuart, Campbell, 1885-; Wilberforce, Robert, 1887-; Willert, Arthur, Sir, 1882-1973; Willert, Florence S.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Wiseman, William, Sir, 1885-; Wrench, Evelyn, 1882-1966; Lusitania (Steamship)
- Correspondence, 1910-1957; Series I; 2' (6 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into the following sections:
  General Correspondence (5 boxes): This section contains the major portion of the correspondence. The material is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Microfiche of Willert's correspondence for the years 1905-1921, sent by the Archives of the Times, has been removed from the papers and catalogued as Microfiche No. 52.
  Florence S. Willert Correspondence: This small section contains the correspondence addressed to Arthur Willert's wife, including his own letters to her, and letters spanning several decades from Eleanor Roosevelt. The material is arranged alphabetically.
  Northcliffe Mission Correspondence: This section consists of copies of the cables received and sent by the 1917 special British War Mission to the United States, headed by Lord Northcliffe, for which Willert acted as secretary. The material is arranged chronologically.
  - General Correspondence
    - Aaronsohn, Alex, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      Letters To AW / From AW: 2/0
    - Adams, Charles F., 1912, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/0
    - Allison, J. M., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Club of Paris, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Armstrong, Gloster, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 1/0
    - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 0/1
    - Astor, John Jacob, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      General
      See also: box 3, folder 75
    - Astor, Nancy, 1919, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 1/2
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1913-1915, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 11/5
    - Balogh, J., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bamford, E. S. T., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Barrington-Ward, R. M., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bernays, Lewis E., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Berth, Ian Hay, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Best, ____, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bevington, Nancy Shelley (Mrs. R. Shelley)
      See: box 3, folder 76
    - Bland, Nevile, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Boggs, F. C., 1902 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bonsal, Stephen, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Booker, R. P. L., 1902 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Boston Evening Transcript, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 1/1
    - Braham, D. D., 1910-1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 7/3
    - Braham, D. D., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 7/12
    - Braham, D. D., 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 9/14
    - Brandeis, Louis, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 1/3
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/1
    - Brocklebank, T. Geoffrey, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Brown, Curtis, Limited, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brown, Mrs. V. E. L., n.y. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      See also: box 3, folder 76
    - Brudenell, George, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Buckle, George, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/0
    - Bullock, W. F., 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Burgis, Lawrence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 31a)
    - Burton, Pomeroy, 1917, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 2/1
    - Burton, Theodore E., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Butler, Geoffrey, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Butler, Henry Beresford, 1919, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cardozo, ____, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Cecil, Viscount, of Chelwood, 1936, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Chamberlain, Austen, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - [Charles?], J. R., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Chirol, Valentine, 1910, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/0
    - Christie, Loring C., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Churchill, M., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Coatman, John
      See: box 1, folder 25
    - Corbett, Howard, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 8/3
    - Corbett, Howard, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 11/6
    - Croly, Herbert, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Cumins, H. A. C., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cunliffe-Owen, P. Frederick, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Darwin, Bernard, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 10/2
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 7/4
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/5
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1914 February-August (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 8/6
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1914 September-August (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/6
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1914 September-December (Box 2, Folder 54)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/7
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1915 January-February (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1915 March (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/4
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1915 April-June (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/9
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1915 July (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 2/9
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1915 September-December (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/13
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1916 January-February (Box 2, Folder 60)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/8
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1916 March (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/3
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1916 April (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/8
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1916 May (Box 2, Folder 63)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/5
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1916 June-December (Box 2, Folder 64)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 9/7
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1917 January-April (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/4
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1917 May-August (Box 2, Folder 66)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/6
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1917 September-December (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1918 January-April (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1918 May-August (Box 2, Folder 69)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/12
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1918 September (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1918 October-November (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Dawson, Geoffrey (Robinson), 1919 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/3
    - Drummond, Eric, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - East Grinstead Chamber of Commerce, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Elibank, Lord
      See: box 3, folder 130
    - Empire Press Union, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      See also: box 1, folder 25
    - English-Speaking Union, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      See also: box 1, folder 28
    - Flanagan, J. Woulfe, 1910, 1911, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/0
    - Fletcher, ____, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Fraser, Lovat, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Frazier, Arthur Hugh, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Freeman, George S., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Galland, Maurice, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 81a)
    - Garrison, Lindley M., 1914 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Gaselee, Stephen, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Geddes, Auckland, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - German Literary Defense Committee, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Gibbons, John
      See: box 1, folder 20
    - Gladstone, William C. C., 1911 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Goode, W. A. M., 1914-1915, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Grande, Julian, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 87a)
    - Gregory, John Duncan, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 88)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 0/2
    - Grey, Viscount, of Fallodon (Edward Grey), 1916 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Grigg, Edward, 1910-1911, undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 18/0
    - Grigg, Edward, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 17/6
    - Grigg, Edward, 1913-1914, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 92)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/3
    - Grigg, Edward
      See also: box 6, folder 216
    - Hankey, Maurice, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 92a)
    - Harmsworth, Alfred. C. W.
      See: box 4, folders 136-137
    - Harper, H. B., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Havenith, E., 1914 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Hayes, Barbara
      See: box 3, folder 108
    - Herwarth, ____, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Higham, David
      See: box 1, folder 27
    - Hohler, Thomas, 1915-1916, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 96)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 2/2
    - Home Counties Liberal Federation, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Hornsby, Molly
      See: box 4, folder 161
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 98)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 8/0
    - Howard, Roy W., 1915, undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Innes, Alfred M., 1914 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Isaacs, Rufus Daniel
      See: box 4, folder 157
    - Isthmian Canal Commission
      See: box 1, folder 17
    - James, H. Challinor, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 100a)
    - Jones, Henry A., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Jusserand, J. J., 1914 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Kerr, Philip (Lord Lothian), 1911-1912, 1914, 1916-1917, 1919, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Lane, Frederick K., 1913 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Lawrence, David, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - League of Nations Union, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Leanoyd, H. J.
      See: box 4, folder 134
    - Lechartier, G., 1915, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 0/6
    - Lecture Management Limited, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Leeper, R. W. A., 1933 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - LeHand, M. A.
      See: box 4, folder 160
    - Leigh Bureau of Lectures and Entertainments, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Leslie, Shane, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Loch, David H.
    - Locock, Guy, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Lothian, Lord
      See: box 3, folder 103
    - Lowry, E. G., 1916 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Lynch, W., 1920 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Lystor, G. W.
      See: box 3, folder 97
    - McCormick, K. D., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - McCormick, Medill, 1914, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - McCutcheon, John T., 1919 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Mack, Julian W., 1918 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Mackarness, Roger
    - Mackenzie, J. E., 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - MacVeagh, Franklin, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Mahan, A. T., 1913 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Mason, A. E. W., undated (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Maxwell, William H., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 125)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/1
    - Mears, Grimwood, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Meyer, George von L., 1910 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Ministry of Information
      See: box 1, folder 11
    - Miyatovitch, Cheddo, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Montgomery, Charles Hubert, 1918, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Murray, Arthur (Lord Elibank), 1917-1919, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Murray, Ralph
    - Myers, Bernard, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Nabokoff, ____, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Nagel, Charles, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - New York Evening Post, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Nicholson, Reginald, 1910, 1912, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 135)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 2/7
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1910-1913, undated, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 136-137)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 8/1
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1915 (Box 4, Folder 138)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/5
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1916 - 1917 June (Box 4, Folder 139)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 11/9
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1917 Jul-Sep
      See: box 6, folder 240
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1917 November - 1918 July (Box 4, Folder 140)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/19
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1918 August (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1918 September-December (Box 4, Folder 142)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 0/10
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 143)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/9
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth), 1920 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Northcliffe, Viscount (Alfred C. W. Harmsworth)
      See also: box 6, folder 240
    - Norton, Charles D., 1911 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Oakley, E. T., 1914 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Ohio State Bureau of Criminal Identification and Investigation, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Page, Arthur W., 1915 (Box 4, Folder 148)
      See also: box 3, folder 103
    - Painter, A., 1914 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Patterson, H., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 149a)
    - Percy, Eustace, 1911, 1913-1915, 1917-1918, undated (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Pinchot, Gifford, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Plunkett, Horace, 1916, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Price, H. G., 1919 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Pryor, S. J., 1913, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Putnam, G. H., 1914 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Ratcliffe, S. K., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Reading, Earl of, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Reed, Stanley, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Riddell, George, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Robinson, Geoffrey
      See: box 1, folder 49-51
      See: box 2, folder 52-72
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor
      See: box 6, folder 224-229
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1939 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Rousseau, Theodore